

7513 Northcrest Blvd
Austin, TX 78752
☎ +1.970.397.6542
⋈ olin.robus@gmail.com
ngraphnet.work

Olin M. Robus

Summary

Taxonomist/Ontologist with 12 years experience in ontology and formal modeling. PhD in philosophy specializing in the ontology and pragmatics of the physical sciences.

Skills

Formal/Technical

- Semantic Web Standards: SPARQL, OWL, RDF/S
- PoolParty & Protégé
- o Python
- Formal Logic & Set Theory
- NLP Extraction, Analysis, etc.

Writing/Productivity

- o Microsoft Office Suite
- o Google GSuite
- Graph Visualization:
 Gephi, Cytoscape, yEd
- LATEX typesetting
- Content & Copyediting

Development/Leadership

- Public speaking
- o Teaching/Continuing Education
- Mentoring
- Strategic planning

Experience

Taxonomy Analyst at Indeed — Austin, TX

2019-Present

- $\circ~$ Develop and maintain two principal taxonomies, and maintain ontology layer.
- Research, design, and execute ontology development.
- Incorporate SME and domain-specific knowledge into ontology.

Educational Consultant at Summit Prep — Summit, NJ

2018

- o Tutor high school students over a range of academic and test prep subjects.
- o Achieve high success rates on student's test improvements.
- Work and research with fellow consultants on test prep materials, curriculum, and pedagogy.

Substitute Teacher for New Haven Public Schools — New Haven, CT

2017-18

○ Taught Pre-K-12th grade classes across the greater New Haven school district.

Test Prep Tutor with Catalyst Prep — Santa Monica, СА (REMOTE)

2017-18

o Taught test preparation for the SAT and ACT to high school students.

Graduate Instructor in Logic and Philosophy — University of Washington

2009-17

- Taught college-level philosophy and formal logic courses.
- o Planned and developed course curriculum to achieve specific learning objectives.
- o Wrote, revised, and edited course materials aimed at achieving curriculum goals.

Assistant Editor for the *Philosophy of Science* — University of Washington

2013

- Worked with managing editor to review and publish accepted articles.
- Worked independently to revise and recommend changes to authors.

Research Associate at the NASA Astrobiology Institute - Montana State University

2008-09

- O Published research in astrobiology. (DOI: 10.1007/s11084-010-9210-5)
- o Presented at international conferences in Italy and Switzerland.
- o Liaised between Philosophy and Biochemistry to improve interdisciplinary research objectives.

Education

PhD, University of Washington, 2018

DISSERTATION: Toward a Pragmatic Ontology of Scientific Concepts

MA, University of Washington, 2011 BA, Montana State University, 2008